（ビー）どうした？
What's wrong?
The enemy is disguising
themselves as allies!
仲間に化けた敵がいるらしいぞ。
Maybe you're an enemy!
そういうお前こそ
敵なんじゃないのか？
We can't trust anyone!
誰も信じられない。
What's going on?!
（ナルト）何だよ　これ？
There's murkiness spreading
everywhere!
あちこちで
もやもやしたもんが広がってる。
ばあちゃん…。
G-Granny?!
No! B-Bro… B-Bra…
ノー！　ブ　ブラジャー…。
Bee!
（エー）ビー！　わしを前にして
火影の胸元を見るとは何ごとだ！
How dare you stare at
the Hokage's chest
when I'm standing
right in front of you!
Oh no, Bro! I meant no offense.
I'm just shocked, is all.
いや　ノー　ブラザー！　を噛んだだけ。
びっくり…。
The Hokage's jugs are
definitely immense.
でも　火影の胸　確かにビッグだ。
We're here to stop you!
お前らを止めにきた。
これ以上　先へは行かせん！
You will not pass!
The Secret Origin of
the Ultimate Tag Team
《綱手：これが
九尾の力をコントロールした姿か。
So this is what Naruto
looks like when
he's in control of
the Nine Tails' power…
やってのけたな　ナルト》
You did it, Naruto.
（カツユ）す　すごいチャクラですね。
S-Such immense chakra!
ブラザー！　ナルトを行かせてやってくれ。
お願い！
Bro!
Let Naruto go…
This is a personal plea.
コイツのことは俺が保証する。
たいがい！
I can vouch for him.
That I'll guarantee.
何を言っている？
Silence! We are fighting
this war to protect you two!
お前たちを守る戦いだぞ。
お前らが捕まれば…。
If you guys are captured…
敵の術が完成したら
この世の終わりなんだろ？
The enemy has perfected their jutsu
and the world is about to end.
イルカ先生から聞いた。
Isn't that right?
Iruka Sensei told us!
ならば　なぜ行こうとする？
大バカか　お前らは。
If you know that,
why are you going?
Are you crazy?!
そのせいで…。
It's because of that!
俺たちを守るせいで→
It's because they're protecting us!
みんながやられんのは
我慢ならねえ！
I can't stand it that
people are dying for me!
みんなが死んで戦争に勝って→
If they die fighting
and we win this war…
俺だけ生き残ったって
そんなの意味ねえ。
and I'm the only left standing…
It's not worth it!
俺は嫌だ！
I don't want that!
世界が終わるよりマシだ。
It's better than the world ending!
皆　そう思い　お前を守るため
犠牲覚悟で戦っている。
We all believe that.
That's why we're fighting,
prepared to sacrifice
ourselves to protect you!
そのことを知って→
You think that I can just sit here,
自分だけ傷つきもしねえで
じっとしていられるほど→
unharmed and do nothing
when I know that?
人間できちゃいねえんだよ
俺ってば！
I'm not that kind of a guy!
それに…。
Besides…
Don't try to talk your way out!
You will not pass!
四の五の言うな！
お前は行かせん。
口で言ってダメなら…。
If you won't listen to me…
《このモードに
ついてこられんのか？》
Can you keep up with me
in this Mode?
《なんだ　このパンチ　むっちゃ重ぇ。
What is that punch?
Damn, it's powerful!
もろに食らうとやばい…》
I'd better avoid a direct hit.
綱手のばあちゃんなら
わかってくれるだろ？
Granny Tsunade,
you understand me, don't you?!
俺がこの戦争を止めてみせる。
行かせてくれ！
I'll stop this war!
Let me go!
ばあちゃん…。
Granny…
今は忍連合の参謀として
動いている。
We are now part of
the Allied Shinobi Force.
お前を止めるのが連合の意志だ。
These orders are from
the Allied Forces.
火影といえど　私ひとりが
別行動をとるわけにはいかん。
Even though I am the Hokage,
I cannot act independently!
わかった　ばあちゃんの立場上
そりゃ　しかたねえよな。
Okay. I understand the position
you're in, Granny.
なら　無理やり行く！
So, I'll force my way outta here!
《今度は　もっと速く》
This time, I'll do it faster.
《これで　どうだ？》
How's this?!
雷影のおっちゃん　速いな。
You're fast, old man Raikage…
《いや　むしろ　あの雷影のスピードと
互角で動ける→
No…
It's amazing that when
you're in Nine-Tail Chakra Mode,
九尾チャクラモードが
すごいと言える》
you can match
the Raikage's speed.
忍で　わしより速い忍はおらん。
There's no shinobi faster than me.
四代目火影が
いなくなってからはな。
Not since the Fourth Hokage!
えっ？
父ちゃんを知ってんのか？
You knew my dad?!
手合わせは
幾度となく　したものだ。
We fought many times.
あれに勝る忍はいないとまで
思わされる男だった。
I came to believe that
no one could ever defeat him.
聞けば　ヤツは
木ノ葉の三忍　自来也に→
FOURTH HOKAGE
I understand that Jiraiya
of the Legendary Sannin
FOURTH HOKAGE
called him the Child of Prophecy…
the savior of the world.
予言の子
救世主だと言われたそうだな。
だが　救世主なら　なぜ
今　この危機的状況でいない？
So why is this savior
not around to stop this crisis?
ヤツは　九尾事件で
失敗したからだ。
Because he failed during
the incident of the Nine Tails!
そこからお前は　息子として
何も学んでいない。
You are his son, yet you haven't
learned anything from that.
不確定な可能性で
物事を語るバカほど…。
Only a fool speaks without knowing
the probability…
If that's all…
そんなんで…。
そんなんで　父ちゃんを
知ってるって語るな！
If that's all you can say,
don't talk about my dad.
((クシナ：そして　あなたが産まれた。
And you were born.
ミナトは　そのとき　「俺も今日から
父親だ」って泣いたのよ。
Minato cried and said,
"From today, I'm a father!"
それから　ミナトは　息子のためなら
死んだっていい。
And…
His words were,
"I'd gladly die for my son."
そう言って　強すぎる九尾のチャクラを
半分　己に封印して→
He sealed half of
the overpowering chakra
of the Nine Tails in himself.
世界の変革　それに伴って起きる
災いのこと　マダラのこと→
The upheaval in the world…
Dealing with the calamity
and Madara…
それを止めるのは　この子だと→
He left it to his son.
すべてを　ナルト
あなたに託して死んだの。
Naruto, he entrusted everything
to you and died.
(あなたを…))
父ちゃんは…。
My dad…
((クシナ：あなたを信じきって))
He believed in you
with all his heart.
四代目火影は
失敗なんかしてねえ。
The Fourth Hokage did not fail!
もし
どうしても行くというなら→
If you…insist on going…
この場で　お前を殺す。
I will kill you right here!
おい　雷影！
Wha—?! Hey, Raikage!
そうすれば　九尾復活まで
一時の間　時間が稼げる。
This way, we'll be able
to buy some time
until the Nine Tails is revived.
敵も計画を
先送りせざるを得なくなるしな。
And the enemy will be forced
to postpone their plans!
死にたいようだな。
Looks like you want to die.
Wait!
待て！
ビー　お前！
Bee, you…!
あっ！
（カツユ）助かりました。
Oh… He was saved!
そういうことなら
八尾の俺が死んでも同じ。
If that's the case,
why don't I, the Eight Tails, die?
そうすりゃ
敵の計画とやらも台無し。
Then the enemy's plans
will also go awry.
ナルトが戦場へ行けるよう
俺の命を投資！
If Naruto can go to the battlefield…
my life is one I'd gladly yield.
ビーのおっちゃん…。
Octopops…
雷影　忍連合での相談もなしに
勝手な自己判断はやめろ！
Raikage!
You cannot make
any arbitrary decisions
without consulting the other
Allied Shinobi Force leaders.
総大将とて　それは認めん。
You may be the Supreme Commander,
but I will not allow it!
わしは　この戦争で→
My responsibility is to make sure
we win this war!
勝利しなければならない
責任がある。
そのためなら
なんでもするつもりだ。
No matter what it takes!
なら　八尾の言うとおり
なぜ　ナルトのほうを狙う？
Then as Eight Tails said,
why are you targeting Naruto?
そのときが来れば　雷影として
弟を殺る覚悟を決める。
When the time comes, as Raikage,
I will be prepared to kill
my own younger brother!
だが　今　ビーを殺すくらいなら
ナルトを殺す。
But right now…
I choose to kill Naruto over Bee!
人柱力としての力なら→
Because Bee is the Jinchuriki
尾獣玉をコントロールできるビーのほうが
戦力になるからだ。
who is able to control
the Tailed Beast's power…
That makes him
a stronger military weapon!
離せ　ビー。
やだね　バカ野郎　この野郎！
Unhand me, Bee!
No way, fool ya fool!
お前たち　人柱力は
己であって　己でない存在だ。
You and Jinchuriki like you do not
exist solely for yourselves!
国のパワーバランスであり
里の力であり→
You maintain the balance
of power between nations.
You are the strength of your village!
国と里にとって特別な存在だ。
To the all the nations and your village,
you are a special existence!
お前ら個人の
好き勝手にはいかん。
You can't just do as you please!
立場を理解しろ　大バカどもが！
You must understand
the circumstances, you fools!
まあ　そうかもしんねえが
俺　個人として→
Sure, that may be so…
But there's something personal
called spirit that I can't abandon…
どうしても捨てられねえもん
持ってる　心意気。
それなくしたら　ただの兵器。
Without that,
I'm just another weapon.
ぬぅ！
なぜ　そこまで
コイツに肩入れするのだ？　ビー。
Why are you defending him, Bee?
拳を合わせても　俺の心の中が
読めなくなっちまったのか。
We're bumping fists…
But you can't read
what's in my soul, Bro?
ブラザー。
ん？
((今回も
ろくなのがいなさそうだな。
Doesn't seem like there's any
good prospects this time…
（ドダイ）よく聞け　お前ら！
Listen up!
この中で　ビーの名を受け継ぐのは
たった１人だ！
Only one of you is worthy
enough inherit the title of "Bee."
ここにいる　エーは次の雷影候補だ。
Ay here is a candidate
to become the next Raikage!
ここ　雲隠れでは代々　雷影に→
You all know that…
Here in the Hidden Cloud,
タッグを組ませることに
なっているのは知っているな？
each Raikage is assigned
a tag team partner.
雷影の力を
最大限に引き出すかたわら→
Someone who will bring out
the Raikage's full power.
雷影の護衛役としての意味もある
重大な名が　ビーだ。
And to be "Bee" is to be
the bodyguard of the Raikage.
これから　エーと
お前らの相性を順に見る。
We'll now test your
compatibility with Ay.
このゴム人形の首を　エーと一緒に
ダブルラリアットで　ハネてもらう。
You will team up with Ay
and attempt to behead
this rubber dummy
using the Double Lariat!
いいか　これは左右から
同じ力を加えなければ→
Remember!
To do this right,
equal strength must be
applied from both sides!
切れない仕組みになっている。
片方が強すぎたり弱すぎた場合
切れずに曲がる。
If one side is weaker or stronger,
it will only bend!
まずは　エーと拳を当て　押し合い
力の平均を決めろ。
First, bump fists with Ay and
determine how much power
you should use.
それから人形に　ダブルラリアットだ！
Then execute the Double Lariat
on the dummy!
よし！　早速　端から始めろ！
All right!
We'll start from that end!
よろしくお願いします！
I'm honored, sir!
や～っ！
うわ～っ！
次！
Next!
はい！　はっ！　うわ～っ！
Yes sir!
次！
はい！　うわっ！
Next.
Yes sir…
Next!
次！
おう！　うお～っ！　うわっ！
Right!
次！
はい！
Next…
Yes sir!
次！　今回も
見つかりそうにありませんな。
– Yes sir!
– Looks like we won't find
– anyone this time either.
本当の兄弟がいれば→
If he'd had a real sibling,
こんなことをせずに
すんだのだがな。
we wouldn't have had to go
through all this…
次！
Next…
ら…　雷影様！
L-Lord Raikage…
見つかったようだな。
It seems we found him.
（ビー）ウィ～！
（エー）ハハハ　少し変わったヤツだな。
You're kind of an odd one.
Bump fists with me again!
もう一度　拳を突き出してみろ。
今日から俺たちは兄弟だ
よろしくな　ビー。
We are brothers from this day on!
I'm counting on you, Bee!
いくぞ　ビー。
作戦は了解。
Let's go, Bee!
Your plan suits me just fine.
We'll bump our fists every time.
拳だけで　毎回
オーケー　ブラザー！
Okay, Bro!
さあ　いっぱい食え。
Eat up!
You have to get strong quickly
or our powers won't be in synch!
さっさとでかくならなきゃ
力がつり合わねえからな。
オーケー　ブラザー！
Okay, Bro!
今回は巻物の奪還任務だ。
Our mission this time
is to recover a scroll.
ってお前　まさかそれ！？
Don't tell me you already…
Okay? Bro?
オーケー　ブラザー。
寝たか？
おう。
Is he asleep?
Yeah…
ビーは　いい忍だ
才能もある。
Bee is a good shinobi.
He's got talent too.
あのラップの才能は
保証できないがな。
Although his rapping leaves
much to be desired…
ハハハ　同感だ。
I agree.
おそらく俺の次は
八尾の人柱力はこの子になる。
Probably after me,
this boy will become
the Jinchuriki of the Eight Tails.
お前は上層部から
そう聞いているんじゃないのか？
Is that what you've heard
from the elders?
いや　まだ何も。
No… No one's told me anything yet.
俺の親父も　おじさんも
みな失敗した。
My old man, my uncle…
They all failed.
おそらく
俺も適合できていない。
I'm not compatible either.
いいか
従兄弟として俺の。
Listen, as your cousin…
But look, you have
the Eight Tails under control…
だが今こうして
八尾をここまで押さえ込み→
コントロールを。
いいから聞け！
– Right now…
– Just listen!
Only those who are
Jinchuriki can understand.
人柱力になった者しか
わからん。
今まで普通につきあいがあった
人々の目が変わる。
Friends and acquaintances start
to look at you differently after.
いや　相手は普段どおり
接しているつもりだろうが→
Well, they probably think
they're treating you the same,
そうじゃないのが
わかってくる。
but you begin to see
that they're not.
見返りもなく
自分の歩く先が見える。
There's no turning back.
You can only look
toward the future…
ただ暗い場所へ向かっていく
恐怖と孤独。
One that is filled with
darkness and loneliness.
適合できたのかどうか？
死を隣で感じながら歩く。
Have you really
achieved compatibility…?
If you walk through life
with the shadow of
your own death beside you?
それらにとらわれ
来る日も来る日も考え→
It fills your mind
day in and day out…
and you begin to lose sight
of who you are.
自分が何なのか
わからなくなってくる。
心に穴があいた気がするんだ。
You feel a hole in your heart.
尾獣は　その弱った心を狙い→
And the Tailed Beast waits to
pounce on that weak heart
and run wild.
暴走を仕掛けてくる。
死ぬ恐怖ばかり考えていると→
When you live with
the constant fear of death,
死にたくなる。
you start wanting to die.
でも　お前は忍術センスも
能力も血統も→
But you have a knack for ninjutsu,
you have the skill
and the ancestry…
You have everything
going for you!
人徳も　すべてを持ってる。
ああ　だから
そうして合理的に→
Yeah… That's exactly
the reasoning they used
when they chose me as
the Eight Tails' Jinchuriki. But…
八尾の人柱力として
選ばれた。　だが。
人柱力に本当に必要なものは
そんなものではない。
that's not what's essential
to become a Jinchuriki.
じゃあ何なんだ？
So what is it?
その心の穴を埋められる
何かだ。
Having something that can
fill the void in your heart!
What is this "something"?
何かって何なんだ？
何かだ　それさえ見つかれば→
Just "something"!
If I can find it,
I feel I can stay strong.
強くいられる気がする。
ビーには　それを見つけさせてやれ。
Let Bee find that something.
また失敗だ。
Another failure.
This time, eight people
were victims of his rampage.
今回の暴走で
８人が犠牲になった。
八尾は尾の数の分だけ→
Because of the number of tails,
the Eight Tails is that much harder
to control than the Two Tails.
二尾より
扱いが難しいらしい。
How long is this going to continue?
いつまでこんなことを
続けなくてはならんのかね。
次の人柱力は確か
ほら　あの子。
The next Jinchuriki is
supposed to be…
you know, that boy.
Such prestige, so immense…
かなり名誉　八尾の称号。
The Eight Tails' name
gave you presence…
Now I offer you incense…
だから　アンタ焼香
ウィー！
Whee!
あの子もダメそうね。
I don't think he'll make it…
クッ！　このガキ！　よくも仲間を！
Th-This kid…
How could he do this
to our comrades?!
テメエ！　どこまでもナメやがって！
Treating us with such contempt!
いくぞ　ビー！
Let's go, Bee!
オッケー　ブラザー！
Okay, Bro!
Bee?! This brat?!
ビー？　このガキが…。
So this means
you're the A/B Combo?
ってことは　お前らが
あのエービーコンビか！？
なら　俺たちの技も
知ってるってことか。
So you're familiar
with our technique?
D-Double Lariat?!
ダ　ダブルラリアット！
♪～
ビー！　まだまだ　俺の理想とする
ダブルラリアットになってない。
Bee, we still have
a long way to go
before the Double Lariat is ideal.
今　俺が
お前の力に合わせてるだけだ。
Right now, I'm toning down
my power to match yours.
もっと力をつけろよ。
You have to become stronger!
わかってるよ！
バカ野郎　この野郎！
I-I know! Fool, ya fool!
兄貴に向かって
バカ野郎　この野郎とはなんだ！
How dare you address your
older brother as "fool, ya fool"?!
It's the Iron Claw for you!
アイアンクローだ　この！
I'll surpass you someday,
you'll see.
いつか　ブラザーを追い抜く！
その立場でぬくぬく！
On that day, I'll be carefree.
この技は
力を均等にするのがコツだぞ。
The trick to this technique is
keeping both our powers equal.
そしたら　お前が合わせるんだよ。
So you have to come up to par!
俺にとっては　それが理想。
That sounds ideal to me.
Talking down to you is my fantasy.
上から目線で
ブラザーに説教を妄想！
ハハハ！　そんな妄想は
ラリアットを鍛えてからだ。
You can fantasize after
you master the Lariat!
Tonight…we will seal
the Eight Tails in Bee.
今夜だ。
ビーに八尾を封印する。
ああ。
Right…
その心の穴を埋められる　何かだ。
Having something that can fill
the void in your heart!
それさえ見つかれば
強くいられる気がする。
If I can find it,
I feel I can stay strong.
Let Bee find that something.
ビーには　それを見つけさせてやれ。
なんだ　ブラザー？
What is it, Bro?
うん？　うん…。
You will now become a Jinchuriki.
お前は　これから人柱力になる。
Things won't be the same anymore.
これから先は
今までのようにはいかん。
It will be extremely tough.
大変なことばかりだ。
No kidding?
It's always been like that.
あっ！　そうなのってなもんよ！
前から。
I'll just give the octopus
a nickname as I rap.
タコにあだ名でもつけてやるぜ！
ラップしながら！
いいか　ビー！　何かあったら
隠さず　俺に言え！
Listen up, Bee…
Always tell me everything, got it?
お前は　俺にとって
特別な存在だ。
You are special to me!
俺たちは　最強のタッグだ。
We are the ultimate tag team.
鉄甲封印とはいえ→
Even if he does have
the Steel Shell Seal,
I wouldn't be surprised if
the Eight Tails starts acting up.
そろそろ八尾が暴走しても
おかしくない頃だぞ。
常に見張っておかなければな。
We'd better stay on it
and watch him.
うっ　ウィー！
Wheee!
The Eight Tails is me,
the cool Killer Bee!
八尾がサビの　キラービーだぜ　俺様が！
おっ　イエーイ！
Yay!
この黄色い髪に瞬身の術。
The blonde hair and
the Teleportation Jutsu!
That's definitely
the Yellow Flash, right?!
間違いなく黄色い閃光だろ！
Then we've gotta
get out of here!
なら逃げるって
相場が決まってるぞ！
So he's the one who
singlehandedly prevented
そうか　コイツが九尾奪取任務を
１人で阻止した忍か。
the recovery of the Nine Tails!
And you are Unruly Ay,
（ミナト）あなたこそ
雲隠れ三代目　雷影の実子→
son of the Hidden Cloud's
Third Raikage.
きかん坊のエーですね。
噂では　かなりの早技と…。
Rumors say that
you are extremely fast yourself.
フンッ　ブラザーと俺がいるならやれるぜ
バカ野郎　この野郎。
With Brother and me,
we're gonna get you, fool ya fool!
みんなは動かないでくれ。
Everyone, stay out of this.
俺がやる！
I will take care of this!
《俺の最速をかわしただと！？》
He countered me
at my top speed?
What's this?
これは…。
すまん　ビー　大丈夫か？
Forgive me, Bee.
Are you all right?!
No way…
まさか…。
コイツ…。
Is he…
the Eight Tails' Jinchuriki?!
もしかして八尾の人柱力か？
It's the signal to evacuate!
撤退の合図だ！
ミナト　ここは　いったん引くぞ！
Minato!
We'll retreat for now!
こんなもん屁でもない。
This is child's play!
八尾がサビのキラービーだぜ　俺様。
Eight Tails is the cool Killer Bee…
That's me!
すばらしき武勇です。
You have amazing prowess.
Not as the Jinchuriki
of the Eight Tails…
八尾の人柱力としてではなく
一忍として→
強いものをお持ちのようだ。
フンッ　コイツは才能なら俺以上だ。
いや　そうではなく→
もっと大切なものを
すでに持ってる。
ん？
エー。
あなたには　いい身内がいる。
私にも。
とにかく次に会うときは→
互いに影の名をかけたものに
なるでしょう。
弟さんにとって
大切なものが何なのか→
あなたが早く気づかなければ→
彼は人柱力でも
人でもなくなりますよ。
フンッ　たわごとを言って
ごまかしても逃がしはせんぞ。
《瞬身の術で飛ぶのは
クナイの場所だ。
マーキングの術式がかかれてる
クナイの場所は　ほぼ把握した。
次に　どれかのクナイのところに
現れると決まっているなら→
俺の最速でやれる》
俺も　いろいろ
背負ってるものがあるから。
《飛べ！
さぁ　どのクナイだ？》
失敗はしないよ。
あっ　これは…。
八尾の尾足に瞬身の術式が！
《あのときか》
相討ちなら覚悟。
刺し合うか？　相互。
敵だけど　キミは気に入ったよ。
(まさに忍キラーな動きだよ))
＜昭和３０年代と　４０年代の
思い出の名曲を大特集。
当時　青春時代を送っていた
皆さん方が→
街頭インタビュー　インターネット調査に参加。
そして
当時のレコード売り上げを加え…＞
＜　お宝映像とスタジオライブで
青春の日々がよみがえる３時間。
２０年分の名曲を
たっぷりお届けします＞